Yu Dong (Robert), Ph.D. & MBA

Cloud/SDN R&D Software Engineer Manager Hewlett Packard Enterprise Palo Alto, CA

U.S. Permanent Resident Email: dongvu6@vahoo.com Phone: 3058013490

Background Summary

I am passionate about adopting a diverse mix of IT expertise, industry experience and MBA knowledge to effectively grow the existing business, as well as guiding innovation investments that could lead to business breakthroughs and shake up business models. I am currently a software engineer Manager at HP Enterprise working on Openstack neutron and SDN controller/apps. I am the inventor and developer of cTCP, an open source transport protocol, at FIU where I earned Ph.D. in speedy 3 and ½ years. I co-authored research papers that have received over 50 citations, and served on program committees of influential academic conferences. I am also an MBA from Haas Business School, University of California Berkeley.

Industry Experience

Hewlett Pachard Enterprise

Palo Alto, CA

2015-Now

Cloud/SDN R&D Software Engineer Manager, HP networking

Building a top-notch R&D team for HP Networking SDN Controller and Openstack Neutron in Palo Alto, CA.

- Manage a multi-national software engineer team (~10 engineers representing 5 countries) and focus on development of both open source (Openstack) cloud platform and industry leading SDN controller;
- Drive business-critical software planning and implementation in HP VAN SDN controller as well as industry's first SDN app
- Define roadmap and lead development on key Openstack features, like DVR (Distributed Virtual Router) and SFC (Service Function Chaining);
- Lead formal engagement efforts around architect and advisory support for Global enterprise theater clients across a wide array of industries (Financial, Retail, Automotive).

Cisco Systems, Inc San Jose, CA

Senior Product Manager, Enterprise Cloud Business Unit

2015

Drive growth and margin of product lines with annual revenues of \$600M.

- Ensure competitive positioning, pricing and promotion of Storage networking products.
- Influence roadmaps and product positioning in full offer DC cloud solutions:
- Drive product strategy around OpenStack integration and inclusion in OpenStack releases for Cinder project.
- Drive new product launches, trade shows and brief industry analysts and press on new product offerings.
- Advise and negotiate with sale account managers in negotiating large software deals and discounts for enterprise customers.
- Socialize product strategy and roadmap with channel partners, emerging countries, executive customers and sales team.

Cisco Systems, Inc

San Jose, CA

Software Engineer Manager/Tech-Lead, Enterprise Cloud Business Unit

2010-2015

Responsible for managing engineering teams, executing/delivering product initiatives, and providing thought leadership and technical strategy from architecture to feature design.

- Manage a high-performing engineer team with high team satisfaction level. My team won multiple top awards in recent Cisco tech competitions;
- Define strategic roadmap and own multiple business-critical network virtualization features (e.g., VXLAN, FabricPath, vPC/vPC+, L2 Multicast, IVR) for a \$2 billion enterprise cloud networking product (Nexus 7000) line;
- Drive a cross-function (around 30 people, including Dev, Test, Program and Product) project to improve layer-2 forwarding performance on NxOS, the most scalable cloud-networking platform in the industry. The project achieved 600% scalability improvement and near-zero (<50ms) convergence performance within 2 years;
- Invent and architect a few SDN/NFV related innovations, focusing on switch virtualization, troubleshooting automation and real-time system orchestration in public and private cloud. 2 of them have already been deployed in Cisco internal cloud and used by hundreds of engineers/QAs/TACs on daily basis;
- Won 12 times Cisco CAP Awards on outstanding performance since 2007;

Cisco Systems, Inc San Jose, CA 2007-2010

Software Engineer, Data Center Business Unit

Lead developer of IVR (a storage networking routing protocol), a key virtualization feature deployed in 60% storage-network

- Led a 4-person team to successfully deliver a strategic high-impact software feature in Cisco cloud solution within 6 months (2009-2010);
- Won 2009 Cisco TAC Award, a rare (1/800) engineer award in recognition of technology expertise and customer centric ownership:

Education

University of California Berkeley, Haas School of Business

Berkeley, CA

Master of Business Administration, with focus on product management and strategy

2012-2015

- 2013 Berkeley VCIC (Venture Capital Investment Competition) Finalist: Final 6 among 30 selected Berkeley student teams, competing for the best of performing due diligence and analyzing high tech/healthcare investments for start-ups;
- 2013-2014 Vice President of EWMBA Association, with focus on Diversity;
- 2015 Finalist of Lean Launchpad Program (Berkeley startup competition): founding team member and product/engineer lead of a healthy food-delivery startup (180eats.com, acquired by LOKL in June, 2015);

Florida International University

Miami, FL

Ph.D. of Electrical Engineering Master of Computer Engineering, Major in Telecommunications 2003-2007 2003-2005

- Presidential Enhanced Assistantship. 2003 2007
- Developed concurrent TCP protocol cTCP (multiple path transfer on transport layer);
- Published 6 computer-networking papers in international conferences/journals with 50+ citations;

University of Science and Technology of China Bachelor of Computer Science (5 year program) Hefei, China 1998-2003

Skills

- Engineering leadership and management at public (F500) and private (startup) companies;
- Expert experience with building large-scale cloud networking systems:

Tech stack: Openstack, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Docker, MongoDB, Django, Flask

- Hands-on experiences with building scalable e-commerce platforms;
 - Tech stack: Magento, HTML5, MySQL, Node.js, Docker
- Languages: Python/Java/C: with 7/5/11 years of experience;
- Tools: Agile, Git, Jenkins, Maven, Chef;

Selected Publications

- J. Wang and Y. Dong, "A Cost Transformation Based Routing Mechanism and Its Applications on Constraint-Routing Problems," in Proceeding of IEEE 1st EuroNGI Conference on Traffic Engineering for the Next Generation Internet, Page 203-210. Rome Italy. April 2005
- Y. Dong and J. Wang, "Fault Tolerance Study on Large Scale Benes Switches," in Proceeding of IEEE 2005 Workshop on High Performance Switching and Routing, Page 197-201, Hong Kong P.R. China, May 2005
- Y. Dong, D. Wang and J. Wang, "A Concurrent Transmission Control Protocol," in Proceeding of IEEE 2006 International Conference on Communications, Circuits and Systems, Volume 3, Page 1796-1800, Guilin, P.R.China, Jun 2006.
- Y. Dong, D. Wang, N. Pissinou and J. Wang, "Concurrency Handling in TCP," in Proceeding of IEEE/ACM 5th Annual Conference on Communication Networks and Services Research (CNSR 2007), Page 255-262, New Brunswick, Canada, May 2007
- Y. Dong, N. Pissinou and J. Wang, "Multi-path Load Balancing in Transport Layer," in Proceeding of IEEE 3rd EuroNGI Conference on Traffic Engineering for the Next Generation Internet, Design and Engineering for Heterogeneity, Page 135-142, Trondheim, Norway, May 2007
- Y. Dong and J. Wang, "Fault tolerance design for large-scale optical switches," in Journal of Optical Switching and Networking, Volume 5, Issue 1, Pages 51-58, 2008